<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<!DOCTYPE PubmedArticleSet PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD PubMedArticle, 1st January 2017//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pubmed/out/pubmed_170101.dtd">
<PubmedArticleSet>
<PubmedArticle>
    <MedlineCitation Status="Publisher" Owner="NLM">
        <PMID Version="1">28823827</PMID>
        <DateCreated>
            <Year>2017</Year>
            <Month>08</Month>
            <Day>21</Day>
        </DateCreated>
        <DateRevised>
            <Year>2017</Year>
            <Month>08</Month>
            <Day>28</Day>
        </DateRevised>
        <Article PubModel="Print-Electronic">
            <Journal>
                <ISSN IssnType="Electronic">1095-9572</ISSN>
                <JournalIssue CitedMedium="Internet">
                    <PubDate>
                        <Year>2017</Year>
                        <Month>Aug</Month>
                        <Day>17</Day>
                    </PubDate>
                </JournalIssue>
                <Title>NeuroImage</Title>
                <ISOAbbreviation>Neuroimage</ISOAbbreviation>
            </Journal>
            <ArticleTitle>Fluctuations between high- and low-modularity topology in time-resolved functional connectivity.</ArticleTitle>
            <ELocationID EIdType="pii" ValidYN="Y">S1053-8119(17)30691-2</ELocationID>
            <ELocationID EIdType="doi" ValidYN="Y">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.08.044</ELocationID>
            <Abstract>
                <AbstractText>Modularity is an important topological attribute for functional brain networks. Recent human fMRI studies have reported that modularity of functional networks varies not only across individuals being related to demographics and cognitive performance, but also within individuals co-occurring with fluctuations in network properties of functional connectivity, estimated over short time intervals. However, characteristics of these time-resolved functional networks during periods of high and low modularity have remained largely unexplored. In this study we investigate basic spatiotemporal properties of time-resolved networks in the high and low modularity periods during rest, with a particular focus on their spatial connectivity patterns, temporal homogeneity and test-retest reliability. We show that spatial connectivity patterns of time-resolved networks in the high and low modularity periods are represented by increased and decreased dissociation of the default mode network module from task-positive network modules, respectively. We also find that the instances of time-resolved functional connectivity sampled from within the high (respectively, low) modularity period are relatively homogeneous (respectively, heterogeneous) over time, indicating that during the low modularity period the default mode network interacts with other networks in a variable manner. We confirmed that the occurrence of the high and low modularity periods varies across individuals with moderate inter-session test-retest reliability and that it is correlated with previously-reported individual differences in the modularity of functional connectivity estimated over longer timescales. Our findings illustrate how time-resolved functional networks are spatiotemporally organized during periods of high and low modularity, allowing one to trace individual differences in long-timescale modularity to the variable occurrence of network configurations at shorter timescales.</AbstractText>
                <CopyrightInformation>Copyright © 2017 The Authors. Published by Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.</CopyrightInformation>
            </Abstract>
            <AuthorList CompleteYN="Y">
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Fukushima</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Makoto</ForeName>
                    <Initials>M</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA. Electronic address: mfukushi@indiana.edu.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Betzel</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Richard F</ForeName>
                    <Initials>RF</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA; Department of Bioengineering, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, 19104, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>He</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Ye</ForeName>
                    <Initials>Y</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA; CAS Key Laboratory of Behavioral Science, Institute of Psychology, Beijing, 100101, China.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>de Reus</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Marcel A</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MA</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Brain Center Rudolf Magnus, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>van den Heuvel</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Martijn P</ForeName>
                    <Initials>MP</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychiatry, Brain Center Rudolf Magnus, University Medical Center Utrecht, Utrecht, The Netherlands.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Zuo</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Xi-Nian</ForeName>
                    <Initials>XN</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>CAS Key Laboratory of Behavioral Science, Institute of Psychology, Beijing, 100101, China.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
                <Author ValidYN="Y">
                    <LastName>Sporns</LastName>
                    <ForeName>Olaf</ForeName>
                    <Initials>O</Initials>
                    <AffiliationInfo>
                        <Affiliation>Department of Psychological and Brain Sciences, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA; Indiana University Network Science Institute, Bloomington, IN, 47405, USA.</Affiliation>
                    </AffiliationInfo>
                </Author>
            </AuthorList>
            <Language>eng</Language>
            <PublicationTypeList>
                <PublicationType UI="D016428">Journal Article</PublicationType>
                <PublicationType UI="D016454">Review</PublicationType>
            </PublicationTypeList>
            <ArticleDate DateType="Electronic">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>08</Month>
                <Day>17</Day>
            </ArticleDate>
        </Article>
        <MedlineJournalInfo>
            <Country>United States</Country>
            <MedlineTA>Neuroimage</MedlineTA>
            <NlmUniqueID>9215515</NlmUniqueID>
            <ISSNLinking>1053-8119</ISSNLinking>
        </MedlineJournalInfo>
        <KeywordList Owner="NOTNLM">
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Connectomics</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Modularity</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Networks</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Resting state</Keyword>
            <Keyword MajorTopicYN="N">Time-resolved functional connectivity</Keyword>
        </KeywordList>
    </MedlineCitation>
    <PubmedData>
        <History>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="received">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>02</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="revised">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>07</Month>
                <Day>13</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="accepted">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>08</Month>
                <Day>14</Day>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="pubmed">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="medline">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
            <PubMedPubDate PubStatus="entrez">
                <Year>2017</Year>
                <Month>8</Month>
                <Day>22</Day>
                <Hour>6</Hour>
                <Minute>0</Minute>
            </PubMedPubDate>
        </History>
        <PublicationStatus>aheadofprint</PublicationStatus>
        <ArticleIdList>
            <ArticleId IdType="pubmed">28823827</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="pii">S1053-8119(17)30691-2</ArticleId>
            <ArticleId IdType="doi">10.1016/j.neuroimage.2017.08.044</ArticleId>
        </ArticleIdList>
    </PubmedData>
</PubmedArticle>

</PubmedArticleSet>